

# OMAR FARAG

2ND YEAR COMPUTER ENGINEERING STUDENT @ UOFT

## PROFILE

I'm an engineering studnet who loves to work with or on anything practical. I can quickly adapt to different scenarios, and I have worked with many different people on different projects - technical and otherwise - which has gicen me experience working in different industries.

# CORE SKILLS

- 5 years of experience with multiple programming languages. These include: HTML, CSS, Python, C, C++, C#, MATLAB and JavaScript, Verilog, MATLAB
- Accustomed to problem solving using physics and mathematics
- Ability to grasp new concepts quickly
- Exceptional interpersonal communication skills
- Ability to work alone or in a group
- Ability to adapt to different work environments and different work needs
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills

# SIDE PROJECTS/EXPERIENCE

- -Developed a board game (Reversi) using C which allows for 2 players or a single player against a bot using the minimax algorithm with alpha-beta pruning
- Created a 2D platformer game using Unity and C#.
- Created a 2D multiplayer game using Python. Created an Al player to play against players.
- Created a 3D endless runner using Unity and C#.
- -Developed a 3D class-based game using Unity, C# and Blender
- Developed a 2D physics based game camera.
- -Experience creating and manipulating databases in C and C++ (linked lists, binary search trees)
- -Experience with revision control using github

# CONTATCT INFORMATION

Mobile: 647-700-7342

E-mails: omar farag 74@gmail.com, omar.farag@mail.utoronto.ca

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/omar-h-farag

Website: omarfarag.ca

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### STORE STANDARDS ASSOCIATE

Walmart Inc. | April 2020 - September 2020

- Move loaded pallets from the back to the sales floor and move empty pallets from the sales floor to the back
- Restock items on shelves
- Collect carts from outside and bring them inside using power tools
- Sanitize carts and baskets
- Assist customers with inquiries, price checks, lifting heavy items, etc

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

#### Brotherhood Softball League | May 2019 - December 2019

- Discussed artistic goals with client
- Created graphic content for the company's website and social media pages
- Used Photoshop, GIMP and Canva to accomplish the above responsibilities

#### PRIVATE ENGLISH TUTOR

### Self-Employed | June 2018 - November 2018

- Used polished strength in academics to tutor middle school students
- Created a weekly learning curriculum catered to each students' needs
- Implemented various teaching styles and strategies for student success

### **GENERAL COMPUTER TECHNICIAN**

#### Green IT | February 2015 - June 2018

- Involved with maintaining cyber security at all office locations (Mississauga, Brampton, Guelph, Orangeville, St. Catherine's)
- Set up computers, networks and printers for new offices
- Troubleshooted any computer related problems

References available upon request

# EDUCATION

# UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO - ST. GEORGE General Engineering

- Year Admitted: 2019
- Widened skill set by learning about engineering strategies, engineering mechanics (statics, dynamics)
- Incorporated team work into designing flood barriers for the Toronto Islands
- Used MATLAB to visualize data
- Worked for a client (Left Turn Right Turn) on redesigning the VIA Rail website for accessibility
- -Currently working on a Google Maps type application with a GUI

#### ISNA HIGH SCHOOL

- Years Attended: 2015 to 2019
- Lead Executive and Editor of the Yearbook Club (2018-2019)
- Executive of the DECA and HOSA Club (2018 2019)

# AWARDS & CITATIONS

- Valedictorian of the Graduating Class of 2019
- Nominated as Schulich Leader of the Year for outstanding leadership and academics
- Awarded the Leadership award for outstanding leadership within the school